type Question = {
    question: string;
    answers: string[];
    correctAnswer: string;
  };


export const jointdata = {
    questions: [
    
        {
            question: "Site where two or more bones join together is called?",
            answers: ["Ligament",
             "Bursa",
             "Joint",
             "Synovium",
             "Cartilage"],
            correctAnswer: "Joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of joint permits free movement between bones?",
            answers: ["Fibrous joint",
             "Synovial joint",
             "Cartilaginous joint",
             "Gomphosis",
             "Suture"],
            correctAnswer: "Synovial joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of synovial joint allows movement around multiple axes and planes?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint",
             "Saddle joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Ball-and-socket joint"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the most common type of joint in the human body?",
            answers: ["Fibrous joint",
            "Cartilaginous joint",
            "Synovial joint",
             "Syndesmosis",
             "Gomphosis"],
            correctAnswer: "Synovial joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of joint is the elbow joint?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Saddle joint",
             "Ball-and-socket"],
            correctAnswer: "Hinge joint"
        },
        
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a fibrous joint?",
            answers: ["Hip joint",
             "Sutures of the skull",
             "Elbow joint",
             "Shoulder joint",
             "Knee joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Sutures of the skull"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of joint is characterized by bones joined by a plate or bar of hyaline cartilage?",
            answers: ["Fibrous joint",
             "Synovial joint",
             "Primary cartilaginous joint",
             "Secondary cartilaginous joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Primary cartilaginous joint"
        },       
        {
            question: "What lubricates the articular surfaces in synovial joints?",
            answers: ["Blood",
             "Water",
             "Synovial fluid",
             "Bone marrow",
             "Lymph"],
            correctAnswer: "Synovial fluid"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint type resembles a door hinge allowing flexion and extension movements?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Elbow joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Saddle joint",
             "Ball-and-socket"],
            correctAnswer: "Elbow joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of joint is the atlantoaxial joint an example of?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Saddle joint",
             "Ball-and-socket"],
            correctAnswer: "Pivot joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint type is exemplified by the wrist joint?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Condyloid joint",
             "Ellipsoid joint",
             "Saddle joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Ellipsoid joint"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of joint is the carpometacarpal joint of the thumb?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Saddle joint",
             "Ellipsoid joint",
             "Pivot joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Saddle joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of joint permits the most freedom of movement?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint",
             "Saddle joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Ball-and-socket joint"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the primary factor controlling the stability of most joints?",
            answers: ["Bone shape",
             "Ligament strength",
             "Muscle tone",
             "Joint capsule thickness",
             "Synovial fluid viscosity"],
            correctAnswer: "Muscle tone"
        },
        
        {
            question: "What law states that a sensory nerve supplying a joint also supplies the muscles moving the joint and the skin overlying the insertions of these muscles?",
            answers: ["Boyle's law",
             "Hilton's law",
             "Hooke's law",
             "Newton's law",
             "Wolff's law"],
            correctAnswer: "Hilton's law"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint is particularly susceptible to dislocation due to poor shape of the articular surfaces?",
            answers: ["Hip joint",
             "Knee joint",
             "Shoulder joint",
             "Ankle joint",
             "Elbow joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Shoulder joint"
        },
        {
            question: "A lubricating device consisting of a closed fibrous sac in or around joints in relation to muscles is called",
            answers: ["Pleura",
             "bursa",
             "Peritoneum",
             "Processus vaginalis",
             "Tunica vaginalis"],
            correctAnswer: "bursa"
        },
        {
            question: "Where are synovial sheaths commonly found?",
            answers: ["Surrounding muscles",
             "In the brain",
             "Around blood vessels",
             "Surrounding tendons",
             "Between bones"],
            correctAnswer: "Surrounding tendons"
        },
        
        {
            question: "What structure produces synovial fluid?",
            answers: ["Ligaments",
             "Joint capsule",
             "Synovial membrane",
             "Articular cartilage",
             "Bone marrow"],
            correctAnswer: "Synovial membrane"
        },
        {
            question: "What is an example of a plane joint?",
            answers: ["Hip joint",
             "Sternoclavicular joint",
             "Elbow joint",
             "Knee joint",
             "Ankle joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Sternoclavicular joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint type allows for rotational movement only?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint",
             "Saddle joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Pivot joint"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of joint is the symphysis pubis an example of?",
            answers: ["Primary cartilaginous joint",
             "Secondary cartilaginous joint",
             "Synovial joint",
             "Fibrous joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Secondary cartilaginous joint"
        },
        
        {
            question: "Which type of synovial joint is the hip joint?",
            answers: ["Plane joint",
             "Hinge joint",
             "Pivot joint",
             "Ball-and-socket joint",
             "Ellipsoid joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Ball-and-socket joint"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the primary role of the synovial membrane?",
            answers: ["Provide stability",
             "Connect bones",
             "Produce synovial fluid",
             "Absorb shock",
             "Transmit nerve signals"],
            correctAnswer: "Produce synovial fluid"
        },
        {
            question: "What condition results from the loss of normal joint relationship and crushing of the disc between weightbearing surfaces?",
            answers: ["Dislocation",
             "Sprain",
             "Rupture",
             "Subluxation",
             "Arthritis"],
            correctAnswer: "Dislocation"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint is NOT a synovial joint?",
            answers: ["Shoulder joint",
             "Hip joint",
             "Knee joint",
             "Skull sutures",
             "Elbow joint"],
            correctAnswer: "Skull sutures"
        },
        {
            question: "Which joint disease affects large synovial joints such as the ankle, elbow, or wrist?",
            answers: ["Gonococcal arthritis",
             "Osteoarthritis",
             "Rheumatoid arthritis",
             "Psoriatic arthritis",
             "Gout"],
            correctAnswer: "Gonococcal arthritis"
        }
    ] as Question[]
};



//         // need review
//         [
            
//             {
//                 question: "Which type of cartilage is found in primary cartilaginous joints?",
//                 answers: ["Fibrocartilage",
//                  "Elastic cartilage",
//                  "Hyaline cartilage",
//                  "Articular cartilage",
//                  "Perichondrium"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Hyaline cartilage"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which ligament type can return to its original length after stretching?",
//                 answers: ["Fibrous ligament",
//                  "Collagen ligament",
//                  "Elastic ligament",
//                  "Hyaline ligament",
//                  "Synovial ligament"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Elastic ligament"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Function of synovial fluid to?",
//                 answers: ["provide nutrients",
//                  "absorb shock",
//                  "lubricate joint surfaces",
//                  "connect bones",
//                  "form the joint capsule"],
//                 correctAnswer: "lubricate joint surfaces"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "How are joints classified?",
//                 answers: ["By the number of bones involved",
//                  "By the size of the bones",
//                  "By the tissues that lie between the bones",
//                  "By the amount of movement possible",
//                  "By the shape of the bones"],
//                 correctAnswer: "By the tissues that lie between the bones"
//             },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What is the function of synovial sheaths?",
//             //     answers: "Support bones",
//             //      "Reduce friction between tendons and surrounding structures",
//             //      "Store nutrients",
//             //      "Produce synovial fluid",
//             //      "Prevent bone growth",
//             //     correctAnswer: 2
//             // },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What limits the degree of movement in a synovial joint?",
//             //     answers: "Shape of the bones",
//             //      "Adjacent anatomical structures",
//             //      "Presence of fibrous ligaments",
//             //      "All of the above",
//             //      "None of the above",
//             //     correctAnswer: 4
//             // },
//             // {
//             //     question: "Which joint allows no movement?",
//             //     answers: ["Synovial joint",
//             //      "Primary cartilaginous joint",
//             //      "Secondary cartilaginous joint",
//             //      "Hinge joint",
//             //      "Pivot joint"],
//             //     correctAnswer: "Primary cartilaginous joint"
//             // },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What is a characteristic feature of synovial joints?",
//             //     answers: ["Bones joined by fibrous tissue",
//             //      "Bones joined by hyaline cartilage",
//             //      "Joint cavity",
//             //      "Minimal movement",
//             //      "Bones joined by fibrocartilage"],
//             //     correctAnswer: "Joint cavity"
//             // },
//             {
//                 question: "What type of joint is formed by the union of the root of a tooth and the alveolar process of the jaw?",
//                 answers: ["Synchondrosis",
//                  "Suture",
//                  "Gomphosis",
//                  "Symphysis",
//                  "Syndesmosis"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Gomphosis"
//             },
            
//             {
//                 question: "Which joint type is characterized by the presence of a fibrocartilaginous disc or meniscus?",
//                 answers: ["Hinge joint",
//                  "Plane joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Synovial joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Synovial joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What type of joint is the hip joint?",
//                 answers: ["Plane joint",
//                  "Hinge joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint",
//                  "Saddle joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Ball-and-socket joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is Hilton's law related to?",
//                 answers: ["Blood supply of joints",
//                  "Innervation of joints",
//                  "Structure of synovial joints",
//                  "Formation of cartilage",
//                  "Movement of joints"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Innervation of joints"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is the most common cause of degenerative joint disease?",
//                 answers: ["Infection",
//                 "Aging",
//                  "Trauma",
//                  "Genetics",
//                  "Autoimmune disorders"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Aging"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which type of joint allows flexion, extension, abduction, and adduction?",
//                 answers: ["Hinge joint",
//                  "Plane joint",
//                  "Condyloid joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Syndesmosis"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Condyloid joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which synovial joint is an example of a pivot joint?",
//                 answers: ["Hip joint",
//                  "Elbow joint",
//                  "Knee joint",
//                  "Atlanto-axial joint",
//                  "Acromioclavicular joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Atlanto-axial joint"
//             },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What is the function of articular cartilage?",
//             //     answers: ["Connect bones",
//             //      "Produce synovial fluid",
//             //      "Absorb shock and reduce friction",
//             //      "Provide blood supply to the joint",
//             //      "Transmit nerve signals"],
//             //     correctAnswer: "Absorb shock and reduce friction"
//             // },
//             {
//                 question: "Which joint type is found in the sutures of the skull?",
//                 answers: ["Synovial joint",
//                  "Fibrous joint",
//                  "Cartilaginous joint",
//                  "Hinge joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Fibrous joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which condition is characterized by the inflammation of a joint due to infection?",
//                 answers: ["Osteoarthritis",
//                  "Rheumatoid arthritis",
//                  "Septic arthritis",
//                  "Gout",
//                  "Psoriatic arthritis"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Septic arthritis"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What type of joint is the pubic symphysis?",
//                 answers: ["Primary cartilaginous joint",
//                  "Secondary cartilaginous joint",
//                  "Synovial joint",
//                  "Fibrous joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Secondary cartilaginous joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which ligament type provides elasticity and allows for stretching?",
//                 answers: ["Collagen ligament",
//                  "Fibrous ligament",
//                  "Elastic ligament",
//                  "Synovial ligament",
//                  "Hyaline ligament"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Elastic ligament"
//             },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What is the function of synovial sheaths?",
//             //     answers: ["Support bones",
//             //      "Reduce friction between tendons and surrounding structures",
//             //      "Store nutrients",
//             //      "Produce synovial fluid",
//             //      "Prevent bone growth"],
//             //     correctAnswer: "Reduce friction between tendons and surrounding structures"
//             // },
//             {
//                 question: "Which joint type permits sliding movements between bones?",
//                 answers: ["Plane joint",
//                  "Hinge joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint",
//                  "Saddle joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Plane joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is the primary role of the synovial membrane?",
//                 answers: ["Provide stability",
//                  "Connect bones",
//                  "Produce synovial fluid",
//                  "Absorb shock",
//                  "Transmit nerve signals"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Produce synovial fluid"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is a characteristic feature of a fibrous joint?",
//                 answers: ["Joint cavity",
//                  "Hyaline cartilage",
//                  "Fibrous tissue uniting bones",
//                  "Synovial fluid",
//                  "Articular capsule"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Fibrous tissue uniting bones"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "Which type of joint is the acromioclavicular joint?",
//                 answers: ["Plane joint",
//                  "Hinge joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint",
//                  "Saddle joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Plane joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What type of movement does a saddle joint allow?",
//                 answers: ["Only flexion and extension",
//                  "Only abduction and adduction",
//                  "Only rotation",
//                  "Flexion, extension, abduction, and adduction",
//                  "Gliding"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Flexion, extension, abduction, and adduction"
//             },
//             // {
//             //     question: "What is a syndesmosis joint?",
//             //     answers: "with a fibrocartilaginous disc",
//             //      "united by a sheet of fibrous tissue",
//             //      "with a joint capsule",
//             //      "temporary cartilaginous joint",
//             //      "highly mobile joint",
//             //     correctAnswer: "united by a sheet of fibrous tissue"
//             // },
//             {
//                 question: "Which joint is an example of a hinge joint?",
//                 answers: ["Shoulder joint",
//                  "Hip joint",
//                  "Elbow joint",
//                  "Carpometacarpal joint",
//                  "Atlanto-axial joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Elbow joint"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is the primary movement allowed by a pivot joint?",
//                 answers: ["Gliding",
//                  "Flexion and extension",
//                  "Abduction and adduction",
//                  "Rotation",
//                  "Circumduction"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Rotation"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What is the most prominent fontanelle in a newborn's cranium?",
//                 answers: ["Posterior fontanelle",
//                  "Sphenoidal fontanelle",
//                  "Mastoid fontanelle",
//                  "Anterior fontanelle",
//                  "Lateral fontanelle"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Anterior fontanelle"
//             },
//             {
//                 question: "What type of joint is the knee joint?",
//                 answers: ["Plane joint",
//                  "Hinge joint",
//                  "Pivot joint",
//                  "Saddle joint",
//                  "Ball-and-socket joint"],
//                 correctAnswer: "Hinge joint"
//             }
//         ]
            
    
// ]}